Nope, I can't get it over.
I don't seem to be a host. Oh,
here, let me make you a host.
Yeah, I can let people in now.
Yeah, I got 'em.
Hello. Good
Afternoon. Morning.
Happy Monday.
Yes, Monday, Monday after an hour change.
That's right. That threw me for a curve ball.
My dog was confused too.
Oh, as was mine. I was like, already. Okay.
Quick question. How is Mexico, given everything
that we read in the paper, you guys are inland and,
but assuming you're in Mexico now,
I'm actually in Canada now,
but, uh, we left right as that was happening.
And yeah, everything was fine.
Um, it's massively overblown by the media.
A few cars on fire in solidarity.
Got it. Hi. Hey, Benny.
Hello. All right,
well, I think we can get started.
Welcome everyone.
Uh, today is session 11
and our second to last session of the Empower Labs program.
Uh, this is our final week together.
Uh, today marks one
of the final steps in our time together all the frameworks,
prompts, and exercises from the past 10 weeks,
were leading us here to sustainable AI integration.
Uh, Hayden will be leading us
through the practical application of what you've learned.
The key question for all of you is
how do you implement your action plan
and what are your next steps post cohort?
Um, we've covered significant ground progressing from the
fundamentals, uh, including understanding ai,
building your master prompt,
and integrating your business context into Claude using
the Empower framework.
And the team and I are very excited for today's session.
It's the crucial step
for achieving clarity in defining the next steps.
Moving from you, moving you from cohort participant
to AI implementer.
Uh, I'd like to check on progress, uh,
rather than look at last week's session.
Instead, uh, I'd like to check
and see which of the exercises over the last seven weeks
you've had a chance to complete.
So it looks just a bit different today. Uh, and here we go.
So feel free to select all that apply.
All right. Right. I'm gonna end the poll in just one moment
and share the results.
So it looks like, uh, folks are, uh, you know,
working through, and that is,
let me just stop sharing this.
Hmm. Most folks are still working
through the curriculum material.
Uh, and that's to be expected.
Uh, please remember that this is not a race.
Uh, you'll continue to have access to the
exercises over the next few months, um,
and, uh, that'll allow you
to complete the exercises at your own pace.
Uh, this is a transformative process
that really does encourage deep
and critical thinking about your business,
and it really ought not to be rushed.
Uh, today's session will cover master prompt, uh,
implementation, and a stage three demo, uh,
which you all have access to, Hayden will walk us
through adding your company's master prompt using the, uh,
AI chat building individual SOPs,
and updating your master prompt with it,
uh, from within the chat.
Uh, and with that, I will send it over to Hayden.
All right. Yeah. So there's three parts to this.
Um, and then on Friday we will expand quite a
bit on sort of the team, uh, side of it,
but we'll kind of start it today.
Um, but firstly, let's talk about our master prompt.
So there's a piece of homework, um, that we've added
to the session, uh, which is going to, uh,
basically allow you to kind of clean up your master prompt.
We'll get to that in a second. Um,
but going forward, uh,
there are typically three different options on how to work
with a master prompts and, uh, involve your team.
Um, so the first option is to keep doing exactly
what you've been doing, uh, which is just keep it in a cloud
project or added to a chat GPT project or a Gemini gem.
Um, obviously the, the negatives there is that you're kind
of stay confined there.
Um, you're working within some of the
constraints that Claude has.
So some of those constraints are very difficult
to update your master prompt.
You basically have to, um, you know, kind of delete files
and update new files.
I can show people how to do that if they're curious,
um, how to do it a little bit faster.
Um, this is a decent option if it's just you,
if you're a solar printer, or maybe if it's just you
and a partner, uh, or you and maybe one or two employees.
Um, the second option would be quite similar,
but a little bit more advanced, um, which is,
you still keep it in, in Claude.
Um, but instead of using sort of MD files
and attaching MD files, uh, you make each file a Google Doc.
Um, and that allows you to use Google Docs integrations
to try to keep those, to update those files.
Um, outside of just Claude, um, again,
we can talk about that.
Um, the third option is to use stage three
or to create a similar, uh, sort
of business intelligence platform.
Uh, you can vibe code your own, uh, in AI studio.
Uh, some people in previous cohorts have sort
of created their own notion projects to do this.
Um, the main, the main functionality that you're looking
for is good team sharing and version control.
So you're gonna want to be able
to version control your master prompt, um,
and also probably
to create multiple different master prompts
depending on the size of your team.
So up until now, you have, for the sake of just ease
of building, um, we've added everything
to our master prompt, including a lot of the SOPs, right?
The core processes, maybe some blueprints as well.
Um, so we did that just for the sake of ease of build out,
but it's not best practice going forward, um, to have,
you know, SOPs that you're only occasionally going
to reference within your master prompt just
because of token usage, uh, and context rot.
For those that dunno. Context rot is basically, you know,
Claude may say that you can have a token wind
of a million tokens, but there may only be like a few
hundred thousand before.
Um, it affects Claude's ability to actually find sort
of needle in a haystack problems.
So in your homework, we are going to go over, um,
just some prompts that you can use within Claude to kind
of clean up your master prompt
and, uh, remove some of those, uh, SOPs and, and processes.
Uh, obviously if we're gonna remove them,
we still need to put them somewhere.
So I'm gonna show you today how to put them in stage three.
Um, and then I can also show you if those are,
if anyone's interested in how to, you know,
turn them into skills within Claude,
another concept
and something people may have questions about.
And as usual as we go through this, please, you know,
just add, type a question or raise your hand in the chat,
and we'll, we'll stop and chat about it.
Um, but another, another, uh,
use case here is actually creating multiple master prompts
for different, um, teams.
So, for example, you may have right now a master prompt
that has, you know, sensitive data
that you don't want everyone in your team, um, to access.
And so you may want to create, create a master prompt just
for leadership, uh, and
or maybe a master prompt, uh, for everyone.
But you, again, depending on the size of the team, uh,
you may want to create ma uh, multiple master prompts.
If you have a larger company
and have sort of divisions,
you may wanna have more like divisional master prompts, um,
where you may have, you know,
HR may have a lot more information about hr,
marketing may have a lot more information about marketing,
um, though, you know, it's probably better
to start using skills for that.
Any, any questions before I move
forward on the master prompt side?
Um,
Hi. Hi.
Hi, Hayden. Done.
Um, just wanted to mention not, I'm going, oh,
what is this skills thing?
I don't know anything about that.
Um, so Claude introduced skills probably
four months ago or something.
Um, and basically if you go to Claude,
and
so if you go to your settings in Claude,
you have this thing called capabilities right here.
And, um, you have skills down here.
Oh, it's now in customized, apparently this is new.
So basically you have all of these skills within Claude, um,
skills are also what Claude code and Codex use a lot.
All a skill is, is a, um, it's a.md file.
Uh, and so it's kind of like a saved prompt, right?
Um, and there is a skill creator skill, right?
That you can go and, you know, I'll do this outside
of my master prompt, um, help me create a skill
for hiring.
So one of the skills is a skill creator skill, um,
which basically interviews you in order
to then create a skill that then, then gets added to, um,
sort of the, the customized tab.
Okay? So it's,
you can see right here reading the skill creator skill.
Um, so I could create a hiring skill here.
And then whenever I mention hiring, it knows to look it up
and it basically creates this big.md file.
It actually already, how would
That, how would that coexist with the HR hiring prompt
that was part of the experience in our journey here?
Good question. 'cause Claude already identified
that when I said it, right?
It says, perfect, I can see the structure now,
let me help you create a comprehensive
based on your AI hiring prompt.
Mm-hmm. Um, it already knows about it.
Um, if I created a skill, it would probably look at both.
Um, but it would always look up the skill
and it would probably clarify, uh, if there was any kind of,
um, yeah, if there was a discrepancy between the two.
So would you end up, uh, dumping the, uh,
master prompt if you had the
skill where, where you wanted it?
Yep. Yeah. You can take, take it out of the protocol
of the master prompt that was also all created
before skills existed, so,
Right.
And so that conserves resources, I would expect.
Exactly. Okay.
Thank you. Yeah,
So it's just asking me questions.
It's not doing it one at a time for some reason. Mm-hmm.
Uh, But yeah, it's, it's going, it'll create the skill.
And then again, whenever you say hiring, um, it will check
that
the, um, the next step
of learning AI is installing, um, probably cloud code, um,
or Codex, I would say cloud
because you're already using Claude.
And so most of what you're gonna do there, so let's see
if you open Claude, you don't actually have
to access cloud code through the terminal.
Um, you have sort of the chat here,
and then you have cowork, uh, and then you have code.
And basically within cloud code, um,
it runs a lot on skills.
So you, you can ask it to create skills.
It, it stores your skills in a sub folder.
Um, and so you're, you're basically use cloud code
to make skills and follow skills.
Would skills be the same as creating a template for,
let's say a, a sales brochure outline
that our team has created in, uh, Google Slides,
and we wanna keep that same look and feel?
How would I translate that automatically?
Yep. It could.
Uh, so again, a skill is just a.md file,
and that MD file could be, um, you know, it could be filled
with HTML if you wanted.
It could be filled with any, anything you want.
The main thing is that it's just a MD file with, um, a way
to call on it, right?
So you, you give it a name
and generally speaking, like you probably,
whenever you actually wanna call on it, you should tell it
to use the skill that's best practice, as opposed
to assuming it'll use it.
But you can create a skill for anything.
So Hayden, uh, I just wanna grab a second
and tell you that, uh, uh, uh, you know how, uh, Clive goes,
oh, I'm compressing this, uh, to continue the chat.
Yep. So I learned a hard lesson.
Uh, it's like when that starts doing that, then you have
to create a handoff file, right?
Because you could, you can get to the point
where it can't compress it anymore
and you can't do anything with it.
I'm sure you know all about that,
but, um, so how, what's your practice on that?
What, uh, do you, and you transcended all
that stuff, or what do you do?
Dreaded prompt is too long. Um, yeah.
Yeah. At least in cloud code that's over,
Or the chat is too long, right? Yeah.
Um, so
it happens less and less.
Um, I actually use Codex now more than I use Cloud Code,
and it never happens in Codex.
Um, so that's an interesting tip.
Um, generally speaking, uh,
every single time something like a chat window gets
shortened, I would say you, you lose some
of the earlier context, right?
It's like a broken telephone.
And so once something has been, I'd say shrunk down maybe
twice, I think the best practice would be to create
that handoff file for another chat.
Um, and in terms of what you wanna show, as opposed to, uh,
just relying on Claude to do a good job of it
and know what, what's important.
So generally speaking,
I say best practice is once it's happened twice,
hand it off to a new chat.
Um, if you were like really nervous about it happening
as you go, you can actually have it update
a single artifact, um, with an overview of everything
that's happened so far in this chat.
And you can actually start sessions like that, right?
And just say, Hey, as, as we go along, I want you
to update an overview artifact.
So at any point, if I lose my context, I can just copy
and paste that artifact to another,
to another chat, and it can do that.
Just keep in mind, it's actually gonna use a little
bit more tokens every time, right?
Because it's updating that artifact. Mm-hmm.
Are you getting that a lot?
No, I, I, uh, just stepped in that hole yesterday
and I, uh, I told it, I, I said, uh, I,
I took everything out of there
and dumped it in a notebook, lm,
and I said, okay, you're gonna teach a class on this
stuff, create the syllabus.
I did a pretty good job of that.
And, and then I dumped that back into my new chat
with Claude, and that helped.
You know, everything we've learned,
all the rabbit holes you went down,
that didn't work while we were vibe coding,
although I will confess, you know, I was using chat at
that time and I probably should have been in, I have, uh,
uh, oh, signal died.
What happened?
I have like a, oh, I have a,
a skill called like obsidian ad notes
that I use in, in every chat.
And so I just use that skill
and it updates my obsidian with a MD file with a,
a full overview of everything we've talked about, um,
as a way to kind of store it locally.
Oh, that sounds like fun. Yeah. Within Codex Code.
Any questions on like, the types
of ma like different master prompts you might wanna make,
or does anyone have any, does thoughts on on
how they're going to categorize
and share their master prompts with their teams?
I have a question. I'm still a bit confused, the teams,
so I have clawed teams,
but it seems to me pretty much
what I think you've been saying is just use Claude
to create, and really the way best place
to store things is on stage three
or something like stage three.
Is that a correct reading of your,
what you're telling us? Yeah,
I as, so I think, um, so I'll tell you the,
the constraints you'll hit with Claude teams.
Um, so you have,
will have a lot of difficulty keeping your master
prompt up to date.
Um, because basically one person, I mean,
you have all these different project files, right?
You, when you wanna update a project file, you need
to figure out which project file it is, it's in,
which you can do in the chat.
You can ask, Hey, where is John Doe located?
John Doe doesn't work here anymore.
I wanna update my master prompt.
Um, but you can't actually tell Claude to go up
to update those files, right?
You then need to,
I mean, I understand that part.
What I don't, I do, I, I,
before we were working
with like three independent just Claude Pro accounts,
and now I've set, tried to set it up
and gonna do a Claude thing for each location,
but it's, it's looking to me less
and less worth it to try to separate it out inside
of Claude if I'm gonna be able to do it in stage three.
Um, where I can have access to all the different things.
You know, it seems like I just set up this one for one
of our schools, but it's complicated for me to go.
I can go in, but then it doesn't share automatically.
So I have to do sort of the same thing, take a copy,
take a summary, stick it into my master prompt,
decide which ones go where.
It just seems like all this is gonna end up in stage three
that maybe it's just as well to keep one
or two Claude Pro counts.
And I don't need all the five from Claude teams,
but that's kind of where I am.
Of just what,
what benefit do I get from having Claude teams at this
point, if any?
Really,
I honestly, the only benefit,
I mean obviously you can share your, your project, um,
but you could do that within normal Claude too.
Uh, you can set separate usage controls
and like excess usage for different team members.
Um, and you could, you can track,
you could do that in stage three, how much excess usage.
You can do that in stage three too.
Um, yeah, there's nothing that Claude can can do
that stage three can't do.
So, or, or to put another way, stage three is a complete,
um, it's a complete, uh, replacement
of Claude for teams.
Um, and for a lot of reasons you might,
so I don't use Claude for teams myself anymore.
I use, um, Claude Max, which is only available in,
in personal accounts for some reason.
And so they have a max times 20 account, uh,
which I recommend everyone basically get that
or the chat GPT version when, when you move to cloud code,
because otherwise it's extremely expensive.
Um, so like when I first moved to Cloud code,
I was using my teams account
and I ran, racked up a $250 bill in two days.
I then moved to, like, my developer then said, no, oh no,
you gotta get on a a max plan.
I moved to a max plan
and it's 200 bucks a month is basically infinite usage.
Like, I think I used hundreds of millions of tokens
and I don't get charged more than 200 a month.
You've never hit, you've
never exceeded with everything that you
Do. No. Nor
is my developers.
I I've actually never met who's succeeded it.
So whatever this times 20 account is, it's pretty unlimited.
Okay, thank you.
Yeah, I mean, the other thing is,
is no version control, right?
And, and I think version control is an important feature.
Um, so version control for, uh, master prompts,
but also version control for, uh, actual processes.
And like, you could use Google Docs
and their version control, but it's kind of clunky.
You could use GitHub, but that's kind of too complicated.
Um, so that, that's another, another thing.
It kinda lacks
fm I'm curious, you have a larger team.
How are you approaching sort of this challenge?
I was just wrestling with whether
or not to ask that question, because I haven't had it clear.
I did get, uh, a teams account
and there is some work going on there,
but I haven't released the master prompt yet
to the team leads for these five people
that I'm piloting this with.
And where I'm having some indigestion is exactly
what you mentioned regarding version control.
So creating a, a prompt or a process
and then sharing it with the team for feedback.
They'll play with their own, uh, clogged paid account,
not part of teams yet.
'cause I don't want to infect the teams.
Uh, and then they'll kick it back to me,
and I'm manually going through
and updating the master prompt
with the masterpiece of that master prompt.
Very convoluted, not terribly efficient.
And one of the questions at some point to you was gonna be,
how the heck should I structure this for efficiency?
Yeah. I, I, I would, this is what we designed stage three
for, I would say do it outside of Claude, um,
either in a custom built solution or in stage three.
Um, unfortunately, uh, it doesn't look like Claude
or chat PT r any aren't really going in this direction
of sort of shared company knowledge.
Um,
Would it work if I fragment the pieces
to the respective department heads
and then allow them to keep it in a Google Doc
with version control and then when needed, I
or somebody on my right hand could assemble it together?
Yeah. So yeah, I would say that's, that's one alternative.
The other alternative is GitHub. Have you ever used GitHub?
I haven't, but the team has.
Yeah. So, so GitHub would be,
and again, it's a little bit more complex.
The nice thing is with Claude, you know, all of those,
everything that you can do in GitHub can kind
of be done fairly automatically,
especially if you're using like cloud code.
Um,
okay, I'm gonna do just, yeah,
I'm gonna do like a, I think a Claude code just sort
of class for all alumni, um, just
so people can get started there.
I think that would be super helpful.
Yeah. Aiden, can I just ask a question about, um, use
of Claude Coworker code?
You had mentioned, like for version control
and sharing of prompts, uh,
stage three is probably a lot better.
Um, I am just curious if one of the main reasons to use,
uh, a team's version of Claude might be
to enable the sharing of these skills, uh,
because I think you can share them fairly easily
within your team, right?
Without having to publish it or anything.
Uh, because that's what I'm anticipating doing is having our
team members access the skills that we create
and centrally manage,
but within, uh, cloud code or cloud cowork.
So I am not sure about that. Uh, I know Claude code.
So your skills in code and cowork will be stored locally.
Um, so it doesn't really matter whether you're on a
teams or whatever.
So you can share it with people, right?
You can, you can share your skills directory, um,
by default it's hidden in your finder,
but it's called a dot skills directory within wherever you,
you, uh, install cloud code and you can share it.
Um, but I haven't actually checked,
'cause I don't really use cloud for teams anymore.
Whether the skills you create can
be shared amongst the team.
It seems like a logical thing that they would allow mm-hmm.
And answer that. But yeah, check, check it out.
So typically,
Are your team members creating skills themselves?
I just feel like most of my team won't be able
to create skills, so I feel like I'm gonna have to do that
for them and distribute it.
Yeah. There's sort of a natural progression
where certain people on the team within maybe two
to three months become what I call an AI operator.
Mm-hmm. And those then start creating skills.
Um, and they probably create skills more than I do do.
Um, outside of that, I would say like
for the first two months that people are learning,
it's gonna be your skills that you're sharing with them.
Um, just 'cause you're gonna be,
you know, a couple months ahead of them.
Uh, Hayden question in the chat about, um,
storing skills in stage three.
Yeah.
What's the question? Sorry, I don't have my chat.
Uh, can we store skills in stage three?
Um, yes.
Uh, though it's slightly different.
Um, so stage,
so you can store knowledge documents in stage three
and not enable them
and reference them, which is the equivalent
of starring skills.
So skills is a, is a cloud feature, uh,
and stage three uses Gemini.
And so we, we created the same
chart without calling it skills.
Uh, your internet seems a little bit unstable.
I'm not sure if there's something
that can be done about that.
Um, I can try moving closer to a router.
The internet's better in Mexico, huh?
Yep. My apologies.
Um, yeah, if it, if it continues, has it been like
constantly unstable?
Yeah, you're, it's the, it's, it's, uh, your, your
the audio's kind of little.
Yeah.
Let me try to move, Continue. We're getting most of it.
I have moved closer to the router.
One second. Sorry.
Okay. Um, so
one thing I realized as I kind of used stage three
and used the tools that we've taught here is
that there's really two ways to work with process, um,
with AI generating your own process.
And so, one which we've talked quite a bit about
is this idea of sort of
documenting what's already been being done.
Um, the main help there is
for training and knowledge depth.
Um, so I'd say a few pieces anywhere where,
you know, your hiring
or anywhere where you know people are leaving, um,
that's extremely useful for, it's also very useful for sort
of bottom up, um, downloading
of brains from people on your team as, as they go
through like a similar program.
And so that's something we found very useful.
Um, and it's also very useful if, let's say part
of your plan is exit your business,
obviously having everything documented, removing some of
that risk from, uh, you know, any potential buyer, uh, is,
uh, you know, very, very much worth doing.
But the piece I actually use this more
for is actually installing new capabilities.
Um, so I, I've called this kung fu kits
because just from, from the Matrix, the movie, the Matrix,
where, you know, he plugs himself in
and comes out and says, I know kung fu.
Same kind of idea is if you want to learn a new capability,
um, you can leverage AI kind of as like an expert consultant
to actually create these step-by-step plans on how
to do something using the exact same
taxonomy we've gone over.
Um, so I, I particularly use this when I wanna learn
and test new acquisition channels.
So I don't know about you,
but I've probably worked with a dozen agencies in my life
and it's really like flipping a coin as
to whether or not they're effective.
Um, and I've actually found now I've probably input
or tested about three
or four new acquisition channels using AI as my coach.
And it's way, way, way better, uh, and faster and free.
So, you know, one, one idea would be if you wanna,
if you're not doing YouTube organic, um, go in
and actually outline the process of, you know, from start
to finish of doing YouTube organic, what the inputs
and the outputs look like.
Um, same goes with like, if you're not doing meta ads
and you wanna test it, uh, I'm now, you know,
I've replaced my, my, uh, ad agencies
with internal people, responsible people who are AI trained
and no cloud code well and can learn from Claude.
I figure I can show an example
or even walk through what that might look like from scratch.
So I'll do that. I'll, I'll share my screen
and we'll go through some stuff in stage three.
Um, before I do that, just a, a few things
that we're solving within stage three.
And again, these are, these are problems that
you'll all face, uh, if you just continue using Claude.
And so these are problems that you'll want to solve
with a solution, whether it's stage three or something else.
Um, so the first is how do you properly share your master
problem with your team with version control?
And then the side,
the side question, how do you keep it up to date?
Um, so let me quickly just show an example.
So you probably haven't done this yet,
but on the left side, some people I think have
beta access and know how to do this.
But on the left side there's AI master prompts,
and you can click that and you can create a,
a new master prompt here if you want.
Um, or you can edit a prompt here.
And here you conversion control each of your master prompts.
Uh, and each knowledge document is kind of the equivalent
of a, of a single, um,
like file within your project source, which you can add
and you can enable or disable.
And then you can basically click regenerate prompt, uh,
when you've added new files or, you know, enabled some
or disabled some, and it kind
of compiles them all together and puts 'em here.
Um, you need to set, uh, your,
your master prompt is a default,
which is, there's a button right here.
And what that does is for every team member that you add,
um, if you haven't set a master prompt for them, it gets
that master prompt as their default master prompt.
In addition, you need to set your version control
as current, and we'll, we'll go over this a few,
a few in a few different ways,
otherwise it's not looking at your, at the contents
of your draft master prompts.
So you need to just set it as current.
So again, you go to AI master prompts,
add a new master prompt, add your documents
by just clicking add document.
And you can either copy and paste here, uh,
or you can just upload a file
and then you enable them by default, they're disabled.
You can click it here to enable, uh,
and then you generate your prompt,
and then you set one as your default.
And you said it's current once you,
so another feature that stage three has
that we'll talk about more on Friday, is this idea.
So when, when you have a team,
you can add people to your team here.
So you can invite members. And
there, there are different roles.
So you can have them as admins
or you can have them as members.
Um, admins can see everything and approve everything.
Uh, whereas members, um, can't touch your AI master prompts,
uh, and they only see the processes
that you actually share with them.
Um,
so once you, once you have set up your master prompts,
it's probably time to go to the your team
and basically, you know, add some members.
Once you add people to your team,
there's also something called My Role Master Prompt.
And your role Master Prompt is for each individual person
to add, um, context about them and their role.
This is usually something we do within the teams program.
Um, so as they go through, just like your program,
as they go through different exercises, they get, um,
new files, and that gets added to a role master prompt.
And then when you actually go
and chat with AI at any point over here, um,
you'll see at the bottom
you can select which master prompt you want to use.
Uh, and in this case, I have my default master Prompt plus
Hayden, and that's my role master prompt.
And so based on this combination, um,
it knows a lot more details about like everything I
touch within this company.
And so that's an, an important feature.
Uh, Claude, we, we teach how to do this in Claude
as well in the teams program,
which is basically you keep your project, your,
your company project is your company Master prompt,
and your your personal settings, uh,
your personal preference is your role master prompt.
Okay. So when you go to actual processes, let's say
for example, yeah, we'll do market to lead.
Let's say we wanted to like install a new capability.
Um, anyone have a certain like
acquisition channel, they want to test
TikTok.
What about TikTok? Exactly. Just organic.
Uh, I was thinking paid, but organic
Sure.
Is that the difference with organic is free
and paid is paid?
Yeah. So, or organic would be like creating videos
and trying to kind of make them go viral.
Um, whereas paid would be advertising or like stores.
I actually know nothing about TikTok.
So,
so once you have this, um, if you, in some
of the previous sessions, you would've already had, um,
a core process that you could, um, insert via HDML.
Um, so you, you could have done that,
but in addition, if you wanted to just use this chat here,
you could basically just
because I have my, you know, my master prompt enabled,
I can just say, you know,
oh, as usual, it's gonna ask you questions.
Okay. So it knows I'm writing a book
about this, which is interesting.
It's telling me, you know,
drive into a high value lead magnet or stage three trial.
So these are exactly the types
of questions if you were talking
to a TikTok consultant that they would ask.
Um, but the nice thing is it knows everything about me.
And is suggesting,
What model of cloud are you using for this here?
Uh, Gemini three. Oh, yeah. It is just fastest.
It's kind of the best combination of fast and cheap.
So the agent basically has all sorts
of different tooling, right?
And so one of the tooling here is just understanding sort
of the whole, um, taxonomy and hierarchy of process.
So it's created this version
and it's saying, do you want me to create
the blueprints and guides?
No.
So what does it cost to run stage three? Long term,
Not a lot, which was surprising.
Um, and it, and it gets cheaper as each model comes out.
Um, so I mean, I'd say per user, it's, you know,
just dollars a month.
Don, were you asking from the perspective of us
as potential customers?
Uh, well, I just, I've been like hesitant to commit
to being in stage three.
'cause I didn't know what I was getting into financially.
Oh, okay. Yeah, no, my, my goal
is I'm gonna probably publish sort of a,
so stage three is available for free
for everyone if they want to use it.
And, and as, as long as it's not too expensive for me,
I'll leave it open long term
and give you like, really good export options if I,
if I change that at any point.
Um, my goal long term is to basically have like
a fairly accessible product that has access
to all the curriculum that we have, including teams
and all the curriculum and designing
for like a thousand bucks a month-ish
and access to a whole bunch of other stuff
that's sort of the business plan.
Um, but I'm not gonna gate anything here.
Mm-hmm.
Certainly looks pretty cool.
Absolutely
Ditto. Ditto.
So yeah, ba basically this is how you'd build it out.
Um, it's pretty quick.
Like you can probably get a full process built out,
you know, in a matter of minutes by full process,
I mean like a full, you know, level one through three.
Um, and then, and then it's a matter of, you know, going
through, through each one, reading them,
you know, testing them.
I would say the be that bottoms up is the better approach
to, to sort of process design.
And so having the outline is really great.
Um, but when you're ready to bring it to your team,
like I think that the, the actual team member responsible
for the process should be, should be trained in using it.
Um, stage three has a
curriculum that I'm developing.
So another piece of this is like,
how do you actually onboard team members
and sort of give them quick wins?
And so we sort of create, started creating this curriculum,
which is basically a combination of, um,
circle and stage three.
And the nice thing about it is, as you go through it,
you can actually sort of, you know,
if you create a master prompt, you can actually do
that within the actual chat,
and then it creates the, the knowledge document for you.
And so we're gonna add teams to this as well. Mm-hmm.
And then what we've done,
and we'll, we'll go over this on Friday,
um, sort of and, and how a team rollout looks like, uh,
the thing that I've had the most success with is sort
of training a team
and having them sort
of build out their own role Master prompt.
So usually the first three sessions are, um, sort
of the foundation, uh,
and the idea of like building a role master prompt out.
And then we have a session for the Clarity Board.
And, uh,
the Clarity Board creates opportunities for each employee.
And so each employee will typically have two opportunities.
Um, and, you know, their, their full day and job
and week is kind of already outlined in ai.
And so AI recommends, um, what,
what opportunities they should use to basically save time.
And on average we're seeing probably about 10 hours a week
of time savings being identified.
And then it walks them through basically
how to actually do it.
Um, so same idea, this kind of capability.
And so, okay, they do it themselves.
Um, they do it within, uh, just existing tools
so there's no kind of top down or consultant needed.
Um, and the idea is to kind of do that every 60,
uh, 60 days or so.
And we have this routines feature that we've added, um,
which is basically like AI accountability.
And so it, it kind
of just messages you make sure you're on track,
um, consistently.
And that's also the way we deal
with keeping the master prompt up to date.
Any questions on stage three
before we move into like the team build out side?
Hayden, I had just, what did the chat?
Can you just give us like a rough number about
what it costs to be in the teams thing?
We don't have to talk about it now,
but just instead of waiting till Friday,
Uh, we are doing an asynchronous version that costs,
it's just you join the inner circle
and you get access to all of the curriculum.
Um, and that's 9 99 a month.
Uh, and then we are doing a sort of a custom
cohort plus consulting model,
which is basically me doing a, a bunch of work that's kind
of bespoke, and
so it would depend on the person and the company.
Okay. But yeah, basically we're trying to make it
as accessible as possible, um, so that people can go
through it for, you know, 909 9 a month.
So with teams, uh,
it's very important that you establish sort
of a strong culture, um, of
AI learning, uh, from the top down.
Uh, it's important to understand that there,
there will be AI resistance.
Um, and I personally think it's much better
to just have a, a, like a culture of learning
and, um, you know, use the carrot more than the stick here.
I mean, everyone's seeing like the CEOs sending these emails
saying, you're gonna, if you don't learn
it, you're gonna be replaced.
And not only here, but everywhere.
I, I don't think that's the right way to go at it.
Um, what we've done
is we've basically started with, um,
we, we tried a couple options.
Both have worked, so we started with, uh, volunteers.
So basically saying, we're doing this training, um,
it takes an additional, uh, five to 10 hours a week.
Uh, we're not paying you extra for doing the training, um,
and we still expect you
to still get the same amount of work done.
So you're basically just getting
free training, but you have to work more.
Um, so it's up to you if you want to do it.
Uh, I've found that about 80%
of the company will typically volunteer.
Um, you want to make it as simple as possible,
um, and show them quick wins.
Uh, the way I've done it is I just typically did a custom
cohort where I do one
or two sessions, uh, a week with people.
Um, and
what I've found is that the people who succeed
with it aren't, and,
and everyone who's gone through the teams program said the
same thing, and it's often surprises them.
Um, the people who they think would've been their AI
operators, um, are like a little less
engaged than they thought they would be.
Um, and then people they didn't expect, uh, to sort
of champion AI start championing ai.
So I do think it's important that you, um,
leave any bias out of it and open it to everyone, um,
because you may be pleasantly surprised, uh, to see
who, who really steps up.
Um, I think the, the two things
culturally that really help, um,
AI enablement is a culture of learning within the company
as well as a culture of experimentation
and sort of taking shots
and being rewarded for taking shots.
Uh, so I would, I would say if, you know, great,
if you have this culture, um,
if you don't necessarily have this culture,
it's not too late to start.
Um, the main thing is just to, you know, publicly reward,
experimentation, celebrate, you know,
learning from AI failure so people don't, you know,
feel shamed and aren't willing to take the shots.
Um, and just making sure everyone understands
that process improvement is everyone's job.
It's not one person's job, it's not your job.
Um, so the best thing you can do there is just model
AI usage yourself visibly amongst everyone.
Um, share your wins, but more
importantly, also share your failures.
You know that you're trying new things all the time
and sometimes they fail.
Um, and then invest in the team's AI education.
On that note, Hayden, are there, uh, particular courses
that you might recommend to create awareness and,
and buy in from the team?
So, I mean,
I've always done our own myself.
There, there are, there are some like YouTube channels
out there, and I think some like low,
like low cost school communities.
Um, school is like S-K-O-O-L, um, that teach a lot
of just sort of AI in general.
It doesn't really train an operating system
and doesn't necessarily train process,
but at least in terms of getting comfort with ai, it's a,
it's a very low cost, uh, way for people to, to do that.
Um, what we do is,
is a lot, it's a lot more opinionated, I guess is,
is the right way to to call it.
So ours is sort of a bottoms up up sort of
process in business teaching through AI as opposed
to AI tools.
But yeah, I think there's some good, you know, mark
Khe I think has a decent program for that.
I think it's lower cost.
Um, and then there's a bunch
of like freer free AI communities too.
I didn't catch that. Mark. Uh, mention,
Uh, mark Khe, I think his last name is K-A-S-H-E-F.
Okay. He
has clock Be careful.
Sorry,
Go ahead.
So yeah, be careful about sending employees into YouTube
that you never see them again.
True.
Um, the way we've approached this is,
you know, there's a, like, like I said, it's more
of a bottoms up, uh, like transformation as opposed
to a top, a top down transformation.
My experience with attempting top down transformation
multiple times is that you just become the bottleneck.
Um, and,
and like along with everything else you're doing, um, yeah,
you become a decision making bottleneck more than anything,
but also, also just sort of a, a skill bottleneck
because a lot of people don't know how to create the skills,
dunno how to do this, dunno how to do that.
Um, and so that's why I kind of changed my approach.
Um, what we typically do is, you know, first thing is kind
of set the culture, um, set up a program, right?
And again, whether you go with us
or whether you do your own program,
I do think setting aside time
where if you're gonna do your own program, um,
set aside a time where they do one
or two sessions a week, um, together, whether it's in person
or on a Zoom call, um, we kind of teach
that the whole empower framework
and teach this concept of a role master prompt
and building a second brain.
So allowing AI to download all
of their tribal knowledge in their heads
and turn that into process from the bottom up.
Uh, that then kind of creates clarity boards,
which identifies op automation opportunities as well
as a lot of innovation opportunity.
Um, that was a really neat side effect
that I did not foresee, uh, is that this has like,
made innovation in the organization, um,
really like stem up, uh, from the bottom up
and it's not from the top down.
And most of my organizations kind of me, um, spearheading it
and now it's, it's no longer me.
Um, in fact there's like probably four
or five times more things coming out from others.
Um, once AI kind of identifies these,
it also walks 'em through.
Uh, and we have a program to kind of train them, um, on some
of the basic tools, um, like cloud code,
N eight N et cetera, and creating sort
of workflows and pipelines.
Um, the key thing here is that like start small, uh,
build confidence through, through small wins.
Uh, and what we're seeing now is, you know, in a lot
of our companies, the 25%
or more opex reduction where productivity is, you know,
doubled or more, um,
so in some companies we've seen like a 70% opex reduction
and productivity is doubled.
Uh, obviously that means people get replaced, right?
I'm not gonna cut corners here, it'll happen.
Um, but typically the people who get replaced are the people
who don't join the team program, right?
So the people who don't show the curiosity
or the people who join it,
but kind of like, you know, don't really learn much, um,
everyone else, uh, ends up learning a ton,
um, really enjoying it.
And, uh, I would say that long term, both for,
uh, you know, I'd say ethical reasons
as well as business reasons, I think having some kind
of profit share with your employees, uh, is important.
Um, the democratization of execution
that AI gives everyone is probably going to lead
to a lot more entrepreneurs, um,
because the risk of entrepreneurship diminishes.
And I think if you give people all, all of these tools, um,
it's only, and you don't give them some kind
of profit share, uh, it's only natural that, you know,
they're, they'll have an understanding
of their worth in the marketplace, um, whether
that's working for another company
or more likely becoming an entrepreneur.
Um, so that's something to be aware of,
is like you are arming people with tools to be
to like 20 x their productivity.
Um, so you may have only 12 months
before people, you know, if you don't do a profit share
before people realize like it's, they're,
they're economically extremely valuable.
Any questions about like profit share is, are,
is anyone currently doing any kind of ESOP
or profit share today?
Yes, I haven't
actually done it yet, but I started one in the last cohort
and got advice about how to do it
and to take a percentage of the, you know, EBITDA
and then divide among different people.
It gave some tiers, but uh, I'm gonna do it quarterly
and, uh, feel pretty good about it.
FM care to expand any, um, how,
how do you think about this and with AI and
Well, every, everything you just said is resonating.
I couldn't agree more with the importance.
That is the biggest fear.
Um, philosophically I've never been shy,
even pre AI about investing in people
and if they leave, they leave,
oftentimes they, they come back.
'cause the grass isn't always greener on the other side.
And since we've fostered an open culture
and retention is high, um, I think adding this piece
to all levels of the organization,
profit sharing is mission critical.
So I gotta think through how, how to do that.
Loved your, uh, sentiment.
Okay. Yeah, I would, um, so this is
part of the training is we, we actually look at where,
where do the, from a a bottom line perspective,
where do the opportunities come, right?
Because there's, there's,
there are cogs opportunities in terms of
identifying mix shift.
Like AI's very good at that identifying mix shift
and, um, doing more good jobs and less bad jobs
and identifying marketing to find more good customers
and less bad customers.
Um, there are some revenue growth opportunities though I'd
say that's like probably third, right?
And, and the revenue growth opportunities are basically
identifying cost collapse that AI can do, figuring out
what the level of diminishing return is for
that cost collapse, and then designing systems to
basically collect everything above
that diminishing return, return level.
And you still make it ROI positive, you know, as an example,
if through AI and cloud code
and promotion, I can create 80 videos a month, you know,
just by myself, right?
Uh, and I can make them 80 quality videos a month
and I have, you know, the case studies
and the actual, you know,
knowledge and information to talk about it.
What, you know, there's probably a cost collapse of,
I don't know, 2030 x, right?
Um, but there's a diminishing return ceiling, right?
It doesn't make sense for me to do more than 20 videos
because that's the number
of times I can, you know, email my list.
It's the number of times that, you know,
my list might be engaged by, you know, any YouTube stuff.
So the question is like, that difference at
60, what can I do?
Well, I could create, you know, segmented channels, right?
I could find the ICP
and instead of having an Empower Labs channel,
I could have an Empower Digital marketing
agency channel, right?
I could have an Empower Construction channel, right?
Um, and now I have 20 per right?
Or I could go and create personalized videos
for my customers, right?
Um, because again, you, you collapse the cost of a video
to $2 or $5
or $10, you know,
can you create custom videos constantly for your own customers?
Can you do it for your employees? Right?
So I'm actually now have a weekly thing that runs on Sundays
that interviews me, um,
and then creates, um, a video
for all my employees and goes out to them.
Um, so it is that type of thing.
It's just like when do you, when you identify the cost
collapse, how can I multiply that times like 300, 400, 500,
um, and still make it profitable?
That's where you can bring in more revenue.
Um, and then the biggest and most obvious obviously is like
opex reduction, right?
Which is, you know, most people, well, first of all,
AI's gonna identify the bloat.
Every organization has bloat.
Um, and just that identification
of the bloat is, is probably enough to like drop opex,
you know, 10% or more, right?
And then in, in many other cases,
like the automation opportunities are very real.
Um, there's also just elimination
and delegation opportunities we identify in
that first month typically.
Um, and I always kind of stress
that like elimination is number one.
You know, if you're, how you're track
how you're spending your time, AI helps
you track how you're spending your time.
Are you part of meetings? You
don't need to be, are you doing reports?
No one reads, right? That's immediate time savings.
Um, so I think the 25% opex
reduction is really conservative.
I'd say, you know, 40 to 50 is probably more of an average.
And there are certainly organizations that were bloated.
Like I had one organization that was very bloated
that it was, um, you know,
70%. Um, have
Made, made an avatar outta yourself yet?
Pardon me? Have you made yourself into a,
a video avatar to
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
This, um, so I use Hagen, um,
hey, Jen is so hey Jen for the video
and then 11 labs for the voice.
Um, thanks. Hey, Jen, for like, you need a pretty good,
like you need to do a good job
and like probably get a professional recording environment
for the recording that you generate your avatar based on.
Um, and it's also not cheap.
So like the professional avatar,
which is like the Avatar four it's called,
is about $2 a minute.
Mm-hmm. Um,
which is still cheaper than like a studio, right?
Um, but the way you do it,
and the way I've been doing is when we generate videos,
you take sort of like a 10 to 15 second intro
and a 10 to 15 second outro,
and then you create a bunch of like, dynamic.
I have like 30 or 40 different dynamic templates on
how to display information.
Um, and you'll notice it on YouTube actually,
once you figure it out, you'll notice the
channels that do this really well.
They sort of just have like a 15 seconds at the beginning,
15 seconds at the end, it costs them whatever, $2 right?
To do that. And it looks like, oh, you know, human
recorded this in a studio.
Um, so that's how you do it.
Um, and, you know, probably keep it at sort of like a nine
to 10 outta 10 professionalism.
Uh, if you, if you wanna use
like personalized videos for outreach, um,
there's a tool called Send Potion, which
basically takes a single recording
and then uses Simple AI to like change the, the backgrounds
of the recording and maybe inject like
names and stuff at the beginning.
Um, and it's like super cheap.
It's like 99 bucks a month
and you can use it, you know, for hundreds
of thousands of videos or whatever.
Um, so I know our team uses that.
I, I don't use it myself,
but I know our team uses it, uh, for outreach.
That's, uh, SEMD
Potion. Yeah,
yeah. Send Potion. Yeah.
There, there are a few of them. Uh, hey, Jen can also do it,
but what's Voice one 11 Labs. You said
You did 11 labs.
Thanks. Yeah,
So a bunch of my 11 labs is really good.
Like, it's, it's impossible to tell, uh, if it's me
or ai.
Sometimes you have to
regenerate like a section here or there.
I'd say on an average 12 minute video,
there's maybe like two sentences that I just, you know,
type regenerate the sentence at 10 minutes and six seconds.
Um, and sometimes you, you treat,
you also build a narration skill out of it.
So like, I had a lot of trouble getting it
to like, pronounce, acquire.
First it was Aquira and then it was acquire, uh,
and so you have to like train it on certain proper names
and stuff, but cool.
But yeah, this has been my experience.
Um, top down you become a bottleneck bottom up,
um, has, has worked so far really well for us.
Uh, and you know, I think it's, uh, also makes,
it makes buy-in a lot easier, um,
and gets people a lot more excited
because, you know, they're the
ones coming up with the ideas.
Um, so, and AI is kind of reminding them
and keeping them, um, accountable to the things
that they committed to do, um, that they identified, right?
Big difference versus you saying, you know, go do this.
Not explaining particularly why,
and then having to follow up every week, how,
you know, why are you behind?
I think, um, if you're going to add this
to your organization, uh, knowing what success looks like
and communicating what success looks like is important.
So these are some things that you might wanna look at
is like, how many processes are actually
successfully AI enhanced?
Um, what's your, your team adoption?
Uh, what's your error reduction rates?
How do you track these things, right?
What's your actual time savings per, uh, opportunity?
Uh, what's the speed of new process implementation? Right?
What's does your sort of cycle time look like?
If I, if you wanna create that TikTok, um, paid ads campaign
and you like, how, how long does it take for you to do it
and then actually put it out on the market
and get feedback from the market, um,
before AI versus post ai?
Like in my example, fm like, I could probably, I mean,
that was organic that we were doing,
but I could probably do that in an afternoon
and literally ship something, um,
within the same day, right?
Um, versus maybe I would've gone out
and found, found an agency or found a consultant
and, you know, talked to four
different, five different people.
You know, we've done reference checks,
then finally hired them
and then there was like a two week onboarding process
where they have to learn my company, right.
Um, and then on the culture side,
uh, what, what I've, uh, seen with some
of these engagements we're doing right now is that
actually employee engagement, uh,
reaches unprecedented levels
because often they're not,
they're just not working on these types
of initiatives as a group.
Um, and they're not necessarily spending like a good portion
of their time learning new things.
Um, so that, that's always,
that's been a really nice surprise.
Uh, I always, within the teams program, we basically say,
Hey, you know, every, we encourage everyone
to become an AI operator, right?
And we, we literally show them kind of similar
to this a few slides ago, right?
Like month one is like, document what you're doing,
you know, build your business, brain learn how
to, you know, build a process.
But month three, a group
of you will be like cross-functionally helping other
people with ai.
And month six, maybe that's half of your job
and, you know, month 12, maybe that's your full-time job
and you're like the single most
important employee in the company.
So, you know, we have people post in circle what their,
what their AI sort of path is and their plan is,
and everyone's like going out
and helping each other in departments.
It's pretty cool to see.
So, some pitfalls, which, you know, you'll likely encounter,
uh, implementation fatigue.
You're probably, actually many of you at that point today,
uh, the culmination of like, you know,
a five or six week program.
Um, so people burn out, right?
It's constant change, new technology adoption.
It's, it's overwhelming, right?
And then you find out, oh, you know, 5.4 just came out
and I haven't even learned 5.2, right?
Um, I, the solution here is, is just, you know, be patient,
take strategic breaks, like, you know,
there's some self-awareness, um, to understand when you need
to just like pace yourself.
Um, celebrate your wins. I, I think that's really important.
Like, it's a, it's a massive win to even gotten
to this point of this program.
And like, if you look at where you are today versus
where you were in your understanding of AI
and a standing of business, um, six weeks ago, that's,
that's probably a likely a pretty large advance
that should be celebrated.
Um, shiny object syndrome,
I'm sure we all face this.
Um, basically try to perfect your existing tools,
uh, before adding new ones.
Focus on outcomes. I still haven't learned open claw
for this reason, right?
It's like, there's still enough for me to do with cloud code
and Codex and everything I'm doing that I don't need to go
and, you know, spend 50, 60 hours learning a new shiny tool.
It's, I don't, it's not gonna give me the,
I think it's gonna take away versus add.
Um, I'm sure everyone has their version of that today.
Um, leadership, attention drift.
So you may have other priorities.
A big client gets onboarded, um, you know, uh,
a big project starts, uh,
and AI can fall to the, to the side.
Um, the solution to that is like to just schedule, uh,
regular AI reviews with your team.
Uh, maintain accountability.
So you can even do that once you start the program.
Just make sure you do that on a weekly, biweekly basis.
And then, you know,
team skill stagnation if you implement a program
and then kind of leave it, um,
you don't give it the support it needs long term.
You know, you don't have sort of knowledge
sharing sessions on the side.
Um, you know, the thing could start and end within a month.
So you do need to sort of give it the,
the space it deserves.
So the last section here is sort
of personally staying on the cutting edge for you
as entrepreneurs and business owners.
Uh, before we move on there,
does anyone have any questions on the team side?
Again, we're gonna be going over this
quite a bit more on Friday too.
So there's this concept of like a innovation
bell curve, right?
And sort of this crossing the chasm.
Um, with any new technology, there's sort
of the innovator phase
and early adopter phase, um, sort of majority adopter phase
and a laggard phase across a, a bell curve.
And I, I kind of think of this as like, you know, right now
in this concept of AI for business
and this concept of AI with persistent context,
that is still very much an innovation phase.
AI as a, what is chat GPT?
And can I use it instead of Google
is already at majority adopt right now,
now it's only the laggards who haven't used it.
Um, AI as what are agents
and am I using agents in my business is still innovation.
And so I'd say most of you are now sort
of at this innovation phase.
Um, but typically within as little as six months, um,
you know, that will probably be
at that early adoption phase.
It could be faster, could be slower.
Um, a lot of it will depend on also what the LLMs do,
what major, you know, influencers in the space do.
Um, so your advant your advantage will diminish slightly.
Um, and then most likely,
and somewhere between 12 to 18 months, I would guess, um,
12 to 24 months, this will be common.
Uh, and, you know,
it could be faster if the actual LMS themselves have sort
of team sharing capabilities
and like process sharing capabilities, which I doubt, um,
and like persistent memory sharing
capabilities, which I doubt.
Um, otherwise I think it's probably likely due
to other influencers just sharing this and it becoming more
and more common knowledge.
Your mission is to stay in the innovation phase in business.
And so what that means is you,
you have an advantage right now, so take advantage of that,
but also be aware of sort of the landscape
and what actually matters for you and with AI
and your business and try if in six months, um,
the big thing is gonna be AI agents get onto that.
If the use of codex
and cloud code for non programming tasks
is gonna be early adopter in 12 months,
which I predict it will get onto that.
So just kind of be aware of where you exist in this sort
of adoption phase, uh, and try to stay ahead of the curve.
There's some things that I think are coming, uh,
and sort of some predictions.
It's funny, I did this slide originally six months ago,
and actually all the six months stuff has already happened.
Um, so I redid it.
Uh, so in six months, I think Codex Cloud code, you know,
these basically coding models are all gonna be, um, it'll,
we'll, it'll be in that early adopter phase
by non-developers.
Uh, voice interfaces will get a lot better.
I think we're gonna see physical, um,
tools behind this as well.
Um, and we're gonna see a lot more
specialized vertical tools.
So the AI agent for this form of marketing
or this form of, you know, uh, sales fulfillment
in 12 months, uh, I think safe versions of open claw
and manis style agents will become maybe not ubiquitous,
but we'll definitely be at that sort of, you know,
10 plus percent of businesses are using it.
Um, you're gonna start seeing a lot more specialized, uh,
industry specific ERP coming out, right,
as people are developing it today using ai.
Um, and you're gonna see the integration
with physical systems like massively expand
as open AI comes out with its hardware,
um, in 18 months.
That's sort of my prediction on
where full memory within the LLMs will be persistent
and can be shared in a repository with others,
and at least 10% of people will know how to do this, um,
which is kind of the replacement of
what you've just built, right?
Um, I think team collaboration
with AI will become much more seamless.
I think Claude and Open AI will have much better solutions
for that, uh, than they do today.
The vertical tools that I kind of mentioned are,
we'll start seeing in the next six months.
We'll likely have a massive price collapse with an 18, um,
as more competitors come out.
Um, and then, you know, autonomous, uh, decision
making, uh,
is gonna be probably early adapt,
uh, adoption at that point.
There will be a good five to 10% of companies
that have age five companies we talked about, um,
in 24 months.
Um, I think AI is gonna be embedded
in all business software.
Uh, we will see new AI native businesses emerge as leaders,
a lot of these one person, two person
companies in every single industry.
Um, and then you'll also see the price collapse
of these industry specific ERPs
that were developed a year prior.
So basically, I think all of these, you're gonna see very,
very niche options of software available and built,
and within 12 months, their price is probably gonna collapse
by five x or more.
Um, which is like super
interesting if you invest in software.
Um, like how, how do you possibly value that?
So how do you continuously learn?
Um, you know, new, new tools are emerging monthly.
I think there were
five updates in seven months from OpenAI
and like five new, new actual, like, um,
versions in in seven months versus, you know,
maybe two and 12 before that.
Um, obviously the capabilities are
also improving constantly.
The best practices are evolving.
Um, I would suggest that your learning system involve, uh,
you find the time that works for you.
You know, usually it's morning or it's night depending on
who you are, um, when no one else can can bother you.
And you, uh, spend some time, uh, learning about ai.
So I'd say once a week is probably more than enough,
maybe even once every two weeks to follow AI news.
So that would be someone like a Matthew Berkman
or a Nate, um, can't remember the last, his last name.
Um, any more than that.
And it, and, you know, it feels like you're working,
but you're just listening to gossip.
Um, in addition,
I would suggest at least once a week, uh,
just following some kind of AI tutorial
and applying it to your business, um,
I've found that to be extremely helpful.
Uh, and then anoth another once a week, again, depending on
what your constraint is, um, give yourself time to play.
Um, so sometimes that's give yourself time to play
with a new tool, with an objective where
that objective should probably be to deal
with whatever your largest constraint in the business
is with that tool.
So for example, if you wanna learn, learn Cloud code
or Codex, give yourself one or two mornings
or nights a week to play with Claude co code or Codex
and apply it to whatever the
largest constraint is right now.
If it's marketing, marketing, um,
I think probably that probably represents
a session a day on average, right?
Um, and I think is more than enough for you to stay ahead.
So this is sort of a outline on how much time
to invest as an owner.
Like what is the bare minimum versus, you know, what,
what are some ideas of how I would spend time
if you only had a certain amount?
So I would say the, the bare minimum is an hour
a day, five hours a week.
Um, you know, I think with that you could probably top down
or in, in combination
with people implement maybe one pro process
improvement at a time.
Um, and you could also probably train, train your team
to drive adoption, um,
by simply just having one or two sessions a week.
Um, that's your time.
They'll probably need to spend more than this.
Um, if you can add another five hours a week.
So we're at 10 hours a week now, two hours a day,
I would definitely spend time learning, uh,
co-work at a minimum.
Um, if you're ambitious, you could move
to cloud code directly.
Um, but I have
that in the next layer, 'cause I think it takes more time.
Um, and then obviously still continue the,
the five hour a week, the minimum viable activities.
If you have 15 hours a week, skip, skip code work,
skip code, work completely,
and go directly to cloud code or Codex.
Um, and then if you have more than that, you know,
25 hours a week, uh, I, I would say
there's an opportunity here for everyone to become
sort of industry leaders in AI in their space.
Um, which can bring a lot of other opportunities.
Can also bring, um, you know,
partner would say industry leadership.
There is like revolves around content creation, um,
and actually doing stuff, uh, and,
and kind of showing what works and, and what didn't.
Uh, I'm curious, I mean, we could just chat.
It's a small group. What is everyone, what is everyone sort
of thinking or committing to doing going forward out
of these options or something different?
I upped my commitment to doodling and,
and just, uh, learning, making mistakes.
This Saturday started at 5:00 AM my wife
said, what the heck are you doing?
Getting up so early? I stayed at the computer with, uh,
30 minutes for food
and I totally rebuilt our whole interview process.
Right now everything is recorded
and at the end of any interview, Claude will send an email
to the HR manager assessing the recruiter's performance
based on the seven tiered score, as well as a summary of the
employee as a potential candidate.
And it was frustrating and it was, uh, for long,
but boy, do I feel great that I champion in that.
Awesome.
Can you just say what tools you used?
Sorry, I heard multiple questions, if that was a question
for me, Nancy,
I just asked what tools did you use to,
to set up your flow?
Fireflies, Zapier, uh, Gmail
and Zoom, and that's it.
Did you follow that video that, uh, we did.
I looked at that first. You were on one
of the screens throughout most of, uh, Saturday morning,
and then, uh, then I dropped it
and just figured it out on my own.
A lot of trial and error,
but using copilot in fireflies was super helpful
with how I chatted with Claude as well.
So it was kind of like co feedback with all the errors
that I didn't know what I didn't know.
Uh, Hayden, um, say since I took the first cohort,
I've been fire hosing this stuff, you know, four
or five hours a day.
And, uh, I just, it's what I do now.
And so, so I, uh, I create, uh, implementations,
I do experiments, I, uh,
and there's just like such, the opportunity is
so attractive.
Um, and it's really the,
the limiting factor is time for sure.
Yeah. So I,
I think 12 hours a day is enough
Yeah. So it's, uh, amazing, uh,
opportunity for sure.
Frustrated by, uh, people's resistance to progress.
You know, you were, you spoke to that earlier
and it's just like you have to, uh, you know, learn how to,
um, not look too weird.
Mm-hmm.
Small wins that that's, that's a big thing. Yeah.
Very, very small wins.
I say for us, we're, go ahead.
We're definitely trying to do between 10,
and I'm trying to do between 10 and 15 hours.
Our biggest challenge is, um, is a very lean team trying
to bring the team forward without, you know,
when you feel like everybody's got more than a full day on
their plate already is figuring out how to, um,
squeeze this in because we know how important it is.
Uh, and then also we just have as a, a new business
that didn't have a lot of processes,
and there's so many basic things that we're still trying
to get, um, improved that some
of this is just beyond where we are, but it's very exciting.
So, um, we definitely want to try and stay in that top two
and a half percent moving forward as far as innovation,
even though we're a blue collar business
and maybe have a little bit more time.
I think, um, the way I've always thought about it in,
in curriculum design is I think you can kind
of kill two birds with one stone here in the sense
that like, the, the way we did teams was we teach sort
of the AI side,
but the same time build out the processes from
what they know, right?
So you kind of need to think about like,
what are the inputs, what's the processing
that's happening by ai?
And then what are the outputs
and the inputs here are, are learning
and training in an interview, right?
Um, but the outputs are suddenly, you know, you could say
that the output was, you learn something and
or you could say the output was, okay,
now we're gonna create a process about what you learned.
Or you could, could say,
now the output is a clarity board plus, you know, KPIs
and all these other things, right?
So it's kind of up to your own creativity there.
And so another thing you can do is work with Claude
and actually say, based on, you know,
if you're designing curriculum for your team, you know,
based on the inputs here,
what are some other really useful outputs that we could,
you know, create and give an example or two.
And Claude will probably give you
a bunch of stuff you never thought of.
Okay, so we're running on time here.
Um, I look at this as a ladder, you know,
you were cohort participants.
Now you yourselves are AI implementers,
probably AI operators,
and at least definitely you've started that path.
Um, the next step up the ladder is team trainer, right?
So sharing your knowledge and helping others
in your organization kind of become that implementer,
or else the bottleneck will be with you,
um, from team trainer.
I would say the next level up is industry innovator.
That requires results, right? In my opinion, to do it well.
It requires results in case studies, um,
but it also allows you to, you know, find new partnerships,
develop new products, services, et cetera.
Um, and the last step is kind of thought leader, um,
and thought leader is the point
that opens up all sorts of new opportunities.
Um, not everyone may want to get there.
Uh, I would say getting to step three is, is just,
is definitely enough for most people.
Um, but if thought leader is a space, um, that you want
to get to, it's, uh, yeah,
it basically just means create content
around the stuff you innovate.
So
this is just a little motivat motivational slide, uh,
to not delay just
'cause, you know, I, I know it's, uh,
it's been a long five weeks
and there's a lot, you know, a lot going on.
Um, but every month you delay customers are, you know,
crossing that chasm while you aren't, right.
AI tools are advancing, they're becoming more com
commoditized, and a lot
of your first mover benefits, um, start to diminish.
Uh, if you start executing now, you have a unique,
I would say, 12 to 18 month window of, uh, using AI
to, to drastically increase the sort of competitive gap
between you and your competitors, actually develop a moat,
develop a brand, which I think is really crucial.
Develop an ecosystem.
All the things we talked about, being
sort of an AI first company.
Um, improve the capability of your team,
which compounds massively.
Uh, and if you know a choice, if something
that you wanna do in the future is potentially sell your
business, you know, there's probably a window in time again,
um, where you know, you will be way ahead
of your competition and also be a very lucrative
and attractive, uh, target.
So we're kind of at time here.
Um, I wanna respect everybody's time.
We will go over this stuff
on Friday.
Uh, just wondering if there's any questions
that anyone wants to get out before we wrap up.
Uh, so just letting folks know too,
that we meet one last time on Friday as a cohort,
and it'll be a really interactive session.
So the first portion will cover strategic
alignment in team building.
That'll include more information about the teams program,
but about half of our time will also be spent in an open
forum, sort of similar to office hours.
So if you didn't get a chance to get, um,
the question answered, we can, uh, reconvene on Friday
to look at those as well.
I did see a question in the chat, Hayden, uh,
from Pavlo about clarity, board clarification.
Um, so maybe that's something that we can look at on Friday.
Clarity board Clarity. Clarity, board clarity.
Mm-hmm. Okay. Sounds good.
Can I just add one question that can't be answered now,
but just to maybe think about how you might maybe be able
to address it on Friday, is going through this whole thing
and, and, um, as you're recommending to all of us to,
to be on the cutting edge and innovate and push
and get that leadership advantage, how do you see the role
of AI where the tools
and its advancement is gonna make the thought process
that we're going through now
and all the time
that we're spending doing these framework implementations
becomes u ubiquitous.
So the advantage that we're building now kind
of gets wiped out as AI continues to emerge.
H how does one position itself to be AI first?
But what I've always said to my team is
always human governed, right?
Like, AI is great,
but you have to have the, the human oversight.
But as AI creeps up, how do you address that?
That's the thing I wrestle with.
I can maybe Friday, you can touch on that, perhaps
Not Friday. I have some thoughts
immediately, but yeah, for time. Okay.
If you wanna share, we're all ears.
Um, have you recorded that
question and then I'll, I'll actually implement it
and I'll do a couple slides on that.
That's a good, that's a good question.
Thank You. I think the u the ubiquity
of the frameworks, just as a one sentence thing, um, I,
I don't think that there will be a ubiquity
of frameworks because of ai.
Um, I think the ubiquity
of execution will likely happen through software
and like niche software dominating.
Um, so like ServiceTitan for example, creates a lot
of execution capability and makes it ubiquitous
because everyone uses it.
Um, but if you even ask those people about the processes
that they're running within ServiceTitan,
like the business owners, they have no idea, right?
Um, it's just automatically covered.
So I don't think what you learned from a,
I would say say a business education
perspective will be ubiquitous.
I think that that is an advantage you'll have. Um,
But for example, the, the eight hours
that I spent developing a little interview analysis engine
as I'm calling it, could be packaged up
and sold for, you know, $99 and now it's done.
So that's what I'm trying to get my arms around.
So a hundred percent.
So I mean, if you wanted to create a business selling
that thing, uh, that's probably not a,
a great business or,
or like I said, like the cost
will happen within 12 months,
but it'll happen based on competition.
And so the act cost is not, it's, and,
and that's the cost in both, you know, for the company
that owns it, but it also the the time cost, right?
The company that creates that thing
and then needs to distribute it to, you know,
a hundred million people or,
or 10 million people for it to then have a cost collapse,
uh, that takes a long time.
I, I look at like, you know, I was, uh,
there's another company as well, I,
I'd recommend you check it out, evry, it's called E-V-E-R-Y,
dot to his name is Dan Shipper.
Um, and he has like this $30 a month product
that has a whole bunch of, he basically just has like a team
of very AI enabled developers,
like five people in San Francisco, and he develops products
and basically says for 30 bucks a month,
you can just get all my products.
And he's developed like five or six products
and developing more all the
time as well as a lot of content.
And one of the products was a competitor
to whisper Flow, right?
And I, he, one
of his developers coded it in like a day, right?
But it's, it's a competitor.
Whisper flow and whisper flow, you know, 12 months
before raised $56 million, right?
To code something that was developed in a day.
But Whisper, that was a whisper flow is a really valuable
company because of its distribution and brand,
and they spent all that money on
distribution and brand, not on product.
So that's why, that's like just another example
of like the moat is distribution and brand.
Thank you. Yeah.
Cool. Thank you everyone. Happy Monday.
We'll see you Friday. I'm, uh, we'll add
to circle in within a couple hours, a couple pieces
of homework on kind of cleaning up your master prompt.
Um, and that's, that's it for homework.
So you be nice and easy.
Thank you. Thank you. Have a good week.
Take care. Thank you.
Uh, the internet was pretty s****y. I
Really, Yeah.
Uh, so it'll be interesting to see what, whether it was able
to pick up, uh, for.